# Md. Marzanur Rahman Tanim

House no- 1/1-E, Monir Monjil, Mirbag,

Moghbazar, Dhaka-1217. **Cell:** +88 01673-979478 +88 01733-334760

Email: marzanurtanim@gmail.com

**LinkedIn Profile:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/marzanurtanim/



### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

A confident and reliable professional experienced of creating and implementing policies to do work with conditions, disciplinary procedures and equal opportunities. Extensive knowledge of key processes such as recruitment, grievance, redundancy and performance management. Handles tasks with accuracy and efficiency. Passionate and motivated, with a drive for excellence.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Savers Hardwear & Tools Ltd. Keranigonj, Dhaka.

Assistant Manager, HR, Admin & Commercial (01 April 2019 to Continuing)

#### *Main duties*:

- 1. Communicating with vendors, collecting price and negotiate accordingly.
- 2. Checking of PI, Shipping documents, LC draft/opening, LC amendment, shipment, release for each and every LC.
- 3. Maintain proper liaison with concerned agencies, banks, trade bodies, shipping line, C&F agents, transport agents, insurance companies, etc.
- 4. Input the data of Duty (CD,RD,SD,VAT,AIT,AT) in Import Statement properly.
- 5. Ensure preparing and renewal all kind of Company Certificates from government authorities.
- 6. Preparing Salary Payment Sheet, O.T Payment Sheet, Holiday Allowance Payment Sheet, Earned Leave Encasement Payment Sheets.
- 7. To maintain corresponding Data-Records/ Log/ Registers for different areas as per BLL-2006 as up to date and submit report to the Authorities.
- 8. Assist in Driving employee relations events and activities.
- 9. Making monthly MIS report (Staff turnover, absenteeism, leave status, lefty, maternity, rejoin, promotion, disciplinary action, salary comparison, and other allowances)

# **Kazi Rice Industries Ltd.**

Mohakhali, Dhaka.

# Senior Executive, HR & Admin (01 February 2016 to 31<sup>st</sup> March 2019) *Main duties*:

- 1. Leads the continuous improvement process of reviewing and revamping of Recruitment Policies, Processes, and Procedures.
- 2. Monitors and constantly develops strategies to reduce the costs of the recruitment process through proper Manpower Rationalization in line with business objective.
- 3. Responsible for Learning & Development activities to ensure development of employees.
- 4. Preparing Salary Payment Sheet, O.T Payment Sheet, Holiday Allowance Payment Sheet, Earned Leave Encasement Payment Sheets.
- 5. To maintain corresponding Data-Records/ Log/ Registers for different areas of counseling as up to date and submit report to the Manager.
- 6. Making monthly MIS report (Staff turnover, absenteeism, leave status, lefty, maternity, rejoin, promotion, disciplinary action, salary comparison, and other allowances)

**Key achievement:** 1. Successfully led and delivered the project on developing Job Descriptions of all Departments. 2. Recruited 40 people for marketing department considering the market benchmark and potential of the industry within 15 days.

# Kingshuk Multipurpose Co-Operative Society Ltd.

Mirpur-02, Dhaka-1216

## Officer, Human Resource Development (1st September 2013, to 31st January 2016)

### Main duties:

- 1. Recruitment related task (Design job circular, scrutinizing application, interview call, arrangement for interview & preparing Personal file of new employee).
- 2. Coordinate and organize staff Training and Development.
- 3. Prepare Salary sheet & Mobile Allowance Report.
- 4. Maintain & update- all HR systems including the personnel file.
- 5. Assist in Driving employee relations events and activities.
- 6. Assist Head of Human Resources in planning for capacity development initiative, yearly training plan and others.
- 7. Banking related task (Loan documents collection, Installments schedule collection, Sanction Latter collection, Balance transfer).
- 8. Disbursement related task (Prepare latter & Ouotation).

**Key achievement:** 1. Assist HR Head to develop SOP. 2. Visit 21 branches (out of 25) for the audit and help manager to motivate their stuff

#### Robi Axiata Ltd.

Gulshan, Dhaka.

#### Executive , Customer Service (10th March 2012 to 30th August 2013)

#### Main duties:

- 1. Handling all customer contacts (voice, SMS, email etc) received, by maintaining quality of service and accuracy of information.
- 2. Complaints and gueries receive.
- 3. Analyzing and rectifying customer concerns.
- 4. Updating myself on all products and services and other policies, procedures of the company.

**Key achievement**: Employee of the month 3 times.

#### **ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS**

Exam Title	Concentration	Institution/Board	Result	Passing Year
MBA	Human Resource Management	Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology	3.50 (Out of 4)	2016
BBA	Finance	Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology	3.12 (Out of 4)	2013
HSC	Business Studies	Dhaka	4.50 (Out of 5)	2008
SSC	Science	Barishal	4.63 (Out of 5)	2006

#### PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENT

Course Title	Duratio n	Institution	Topic Covered	Passin g Year
Human Resource Management Competencies	6 Weeks	Institution of Business Administration, DU	JD,HR planning, OS, R&S, HRD, PMS, HR Accounting Strategic HRM, Conflict Management, Work life balance etc.	2019

#### TRAINING SUMMARY

Training Title	Duration	Institution/ Facilitator	Topic Covered	Passing Year
Personal Productivity	Day Long	Quazi M Ahmed	Time & Energy Management, Priority Setting, Focus Point, Accountability, Communication.	Oct 2019

Emotional Intelligence	Day Long	Ghulam Sumdany	Self-Awareness, Self- Management, Controlling Emotions, Self SWOT Analysis.	Aug 2019
KPI based PMS	Day Long	Rupak Nasrullah Zaidi	Characteristics, Scope, KPI Designing, Steps, Selection Criteria, Reward Management.	Dec 2018
Investment Criteria	3 Days	BICM	Financial Market, Investment, Primary & Sec Market, Ratio etc.	Oct 2015
Mobile Banking (Internship)	3 Months	DBBL	Objectives, Benefits, Prospect, Process, SWOT Analysis etc.	Apr 2013

#### **COMPUTER LITERACY**

- Excellent internet communication ability.
- Microsoft Office suite.
- Graphic designing: PrimaryStatistics Software: SPSS.

#### **EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

- ♣ Founder member of a social group WIZARD's (Year 2014-present); it is a social platform based on Bakerganj JSU High School students with more than 500+ members. Organized several yearly programs to sustain unity among school mates.
- ♣ Founder member of "Bangladesh FMCG HR society".
- ♣ Lifelong Blood Donor.

#### **BIOGRAPHY**

- Father's Name: Md. Yousuf Ali Khan (Govt. Service)Mother's Name: Kohinur Begum (Govt. Service)
- □ **Date of birth:** June 02, 1991
- Permanent Address: Nolchiti Kutir, Shahebganj, Bakerganj, Barishal.
- National Id: 7784729639
   Passport No: AD7332947
   Marital Status: Married
   Blood Group: "A+"
- ☐ **Interests:** Photography, Social Services, Sports, Traveling.

#### REFERENCE

Name: Md. Enamul Karim Khan

Designation: Joint Director

Name: S M Ahbabur Rahman

Designation: DGM-HR

Organization: Bangladesh Bank.

Address: Dhaka, Bangladesh

Mobile: +880197-9071586

E-mail: enamul.khan@bb.org.bd

Relation: Family Friend

Organization: Pandughar Group.

Address: House#43, Road#35,

Gulshan-2, Dhaka-1212.

Mobile: +880181-7517475

E-mail: ahbab@pandughar.com

**Relation:** Professional

#### **DECLARATION**

I, the undersigned, declare honestly and consciously that the information of myself stated here is correct, true and fair to the best of my belief and knowledge.

comil

Date: 01 Oct 2020 Signature:-